Guide to the UH News Releases
University of Houston Libraries
UH News Releases
1947-1954
09/1969-067
University of Houston
4.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Forms part of the University Archives. The U.H. News Releases include official university news releases, advertisements, correspondence, and administrative records, dating from 1947-1954. This collection is arranged into series based primarily on how it was originally received.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston
Genre/Form of Material:
Advertisements; Correspondence; Press releases; Records (documents)
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
Forms part of the University Archives. The U.H. News Releases include official university news releases, advertisements, correspondence, and administrative records, dating from 1947-1954. This collection is arranged into series based primarily on how it was originally received. The News Release series is the largest in the collection containing 56 folders. Materials date from May 1950 to August 1954 and are divided by month of the release. These releases cover almost every aspect of the University including announcements of events, articles published by faculty, building openings, Frontier Fiesta, workshops, classes, and many additional topics. Files have been arranged chronologically. The Advertisement series contains 3 folders of advertisements issued by the University and relate to a variety of topics that include registration, course offerings, child care, and many others. The materials include tear-sheets, working drafts of advertisements, and a few final drafts run in local newspapers. The Correspondence series contains 8 folders of material that date between 1947 and 1954. This series is arranged chronologically. The correspondence primarily relates to issues that concern the athletic program including its membership in the Missouri Valley Conference, football schedules, information used in brochures, and a tentative copy of the constitution of the Missouri Valley Press Association. There is also a large variety of other correspondence found in this series including material related to Frontier Fiesta, educational conferences, and career days held at the university. The Administrative Record series is arranged alphabetically and contains 47 folders.
Overall, the original folder order has been maintained. This Collection contains a wide range of materials relating to the administration of the department. Materials include monthly reports, cartoons, and negative lists. For preservation and access reasons the collection has been re-boxed and re-foldered. New folder titles conform, as closely as possible, to original folder titles, except when the original was obviously incomplete, incorrect, or confusing. Original folder and item order has been maintained whenever possible. Exceptions were made when folders were obviously misfiled or when no order was apparent.
Detailed List of Contents
- News Releases
  Scope and Contents
  This is the largest series in the collection containing 56 folders. Materials date from May 1950 to August 1954 and are divided in most cases by month of the release. These releases cover almost every aspect of the University including announcements of events, articles published by faculty, building openings, Frontier Fiesta, workshops, classes, and many other topics. Files in this series have been arranged chronologically.
  - May 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - June 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - July 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - August 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - September 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - October 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - November 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - December 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - January 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - February 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - March 1-22, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - March 26-31, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - April 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - May 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - June 1951 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - July 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - August 1951 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - September 1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - October 1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - November 1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - December 1951 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - January 1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - February 1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - March 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - April 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - May 1952 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - June 1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - July 1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - August 1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - September 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - October 1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - December 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - January 1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - February 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - March 2-11, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - March 12-24, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - March 25-31, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - April 1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - May 1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - June 1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - July 1953 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - August 1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - September 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - October 1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - November 1953 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - December 1953 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Frontier Fiesta 1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - January 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - February 1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - March 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - April 1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - May 1954 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - June 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - July 1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - August 1-20,1954 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - August 21-30,1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Advertisements
  This series contains 3 folders of advertisements issued by the University relating to a variety of topics including registration, course offerings, child care, topics concerning Veterans and many others. The materials include tear-sheets, working drafts of advertisement along with the final drafts run in local newspapers.
  - 1950-Spring 1951 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Correspondence
  This series contains 8 folders of correspondence dating between 1947 and 1954 and arranged chronologically. Much of the correspondence relates to issues concerning the athletic program at the university including its membership in the Missouri Valley Conference, football schedules, information used in brochures, and a tentative copy of the constitution of the Missouri Valley Press Association. There is a large variety of other correspondence found in this series including material related to Frontier Fiesta, educational conferences, and career days held at the university.
  - 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - May-August, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - September-December, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - January-May,1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - June-December, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1952 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1954 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Administrative Records
  Arranged alphabetically, this series contains 47 folders. Overall, the original folder order has been maintained. This series contains a wide range of materials relating to the administration of the department. Materials include monthly reports, cartoons, and negative lists.
  - Agriculture Department (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Applications News Service (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Athletic Negative List (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Broom, Sir Robert-Photograph (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Caps and Gowns (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cartoons (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Distributive Education (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ellington Air Force Base Branch (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Encyclopedia-Houston (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Foreign Language Department (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Frontier Fiesta Negative Lists, 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Guidance Program (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Houstonians (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Houston Post, The (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Jones Nursing School Scholarship-Photograph (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Law School (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Medical Office (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Monthly Reports, June-August 1950 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Monthly Reports, September 1950-August 1951 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Monthly Reports, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Negative Lists, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Negative Lists, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Negative Lists, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Negative List, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Petty Cash (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Pharmacy School-Photographs, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Photography Department (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Photography Equipment and Supplies (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Photography Invoices (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Placement Office (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Public Relations - Directory (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Public Relations - Expenses (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Public Relations - Faculty Members Schedule (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Public Relations - General (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Public Relations - Photograph Assignments (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Public Relations - Staff Meeting Notes (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Franklin Delano Roosevelt (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - R.O.T.C (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Special Poll Photographs (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Speech Department (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Stores - Stationary and Office Supplies (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Summer Centers (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - University of Houston - Information for Book (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - University of Houston - Rules and Regulations (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - University of Houston - Songs (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Visual Education (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Yearbook Management and Finance (Box 4, Folder 52)